<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fiats on The Shadowy Cabal</title>
    <link>https://shadowycabal.org/fiat/</link>
    <description>The Shadowy Cabal (Fiats)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 12:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://shadowycabal.org/fiat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tax the Poor</title>
      <link>https://shadowycabal.org/fiat/tax-the-poor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shadowycabal.org/fiat/tax-the-poor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Restructuring the US Tax Code is always in vogue regardless of which party holds the power of the purse. Cutting taxes forms one of a few planks of the Republican party platform, and much of Democratic policy is based on raising government revenues by taxing the rich. Both parties claim their goals are to lower the national debt and decrease the financial burden on the majority of Americans. We at The Cabal see a path forward towards one of those goals by doing away with the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we are counting the ways by which we can try to tax 1% of our population on 2% of their wealth, going through permutations of capital gains taxes, estate taxes, and higher marginal income tax brackets, we are staring at a solution to the government debt right in front of us, if only we would lower our sights: taxing the 99%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arguments for wealth taxes miss the boat: a wealthy person donating much of their wealth to charity would be taxed the same as one spending on a yacht. This doesn&amp;rsquo;t make intuitive sense! One of these people is contributing much more to society than the other, yet they would be taxed the same. Consumption taxes, to make spending on extravagances like fast cars, large TVs, loud speakers, and other favored toys less practical seem reasonable by comparison. These could then be aimed at favorite status symbols of the not-quite-as-wealthy, such as working cars, smaller TVs, and microwave ovens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Futhermore, the top 50% of taxpayers paid 97% of tax revenue, while the bottom 50% of Americans paid a paltry 3% of the tax revenue.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Clearly this inequality is out of whack! We continue to plumb the well of the richest, taking as much as we can from them. Why are we trying to get water from a stone, squeezing the top for even more when they have given us so much, while the bottom skate by on a free ride?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, these untapped masses are the same souls who want to increase government spending. Policies like universal healthcare, New Deals (Green or otherwise), and Great Societies are fundamentally only on the majority&amp;rsquo;s wishlist. The wealthy minority has healthcare covered, is very happy with the current deal, and would like to have more events with High Society rather than any Greater or Larger Society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To end income inequality, we must tax the poor. Who else could pay for all of this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://taxfoundation.org/summary-of-the-latest-federal-income-tax-data-2020-update/&#34;&gt;https://taxfoundation.org/summary-of-the-latest-federal-income-tax-data-2020-update/&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Money in Politics</title>
      <link>https://shadowycabal.org/fiat/money-in-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 12:14:51 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shadowycabal.org/fiat/money-in-politics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reinvestment in United States infrastructure is desperately needed. Millions of water pipes carry lead contamination and fracking residue to citizens. Thirty-million homes in the US have gas leaks, damaged plumbing, and/or poor heat. One-fifth of those have lead paint. Roads and bridges deteriorate, trains run slowly off their tracks, planes crash. Unemployment and poverty rates are inversely correlated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simultaneously, debt is cheap around the world. Interest rates are at all-time lows, asset valuations are similarly at near all-time highs, and debt is cheap for those who can afford it. Untapped funds are available to any investor who could demonstrate future returns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most practical choice for the USA is clear: Deregulate campaign finance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Political campaigns function by utilizing public resources: roads for door-knocking campaigns, airwaves for media buys, and the time of elected officials. These all have been sorely lacking in public investment for decades and have suffered for lack of funds. Through campaigns, private capital has been engaging in a successful public-private partnership, unreservedly demonstrating its willingness to fund public life, and it should be plain that increasing the supply of political spending will have trickle-down effects on the rest of the economy. The supply-side of this economic market also deserves most of our focus since supply-side economics have been proven through their resiliency to all opposing research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A cursory examination of this market reveals onerous government regulation of free-market enterprise on the supply-side. The supply is still large, despite current legal constraints. Uncontested lower-house seats can spend over fifteen-million dollars, upper-house seats pull into the hundred-million dollar range easily, and even failed presidential primary campaigns can be as expensive as a billion dollars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corporations have no limits to their political spend on individual issues as that would otherwise abridge their First Amendment rights to freedom of speech. Despite this, individuals still have limits on their donations per campaign cycle, set in the low-thousands of dollars. This is blatant regulatory overreach and economically short-sighted. Not only should one contest the authority for the US Federal Government to regulate speech in this manner, these laws amount to a waste of spending on private legal counsel that would otherwise be available for further political stimulus. Obviously, the freedom on group spending should be extended to individuals to fully unleash the power of the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, using a flat cap on donations instead of a progressive rate restricts the speech of the wealthiest Americans. Those who have found success in private life deserve to shape our public life. This is an unconstitutional muffle on the deserving. Why should a banker on Wall Street be limited like a rural farmer in their spending power? Should we not hear their voices more clearly than the poor? Are the successful and blessed to be considered as rational and worthy as the impoverished? This tyranny of the majority, oppressing the wealthy class at society&amp;rsquo;s own literal expense, wealth forcibly bound in financial instruments rather than political candidates, is reprehensible and un-American.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should strive in political campaigns to have an open debate of the most important issues. Taking the brakes off of this train can drive economic activity in media, law, consulting, accounting, punditry, and shadow banking that could not be replicated on such scale with similar investment in other industries. A world where we gag the rich from free expression, lest they make more noise than the rural farmer, is not a world where free enterprise and capitalist competition can survive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, this should also satisfy those who clamor for campaign finance restrictions. When there is enough money in politics, there will be no money in politics. The marginal value of each dollar spent on politics would be so low that nobody would spend money on elections. This is the reason nobody in New York City owns a car: the traffic is terrible, and parking is expensive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>